LISA SEIGNEUR

Chicago, IL • LSeigneur@Live.com • (312) 388-0405 • linkedin.com/in/lisaseigneur

Senior Operations Executive

An accomplished multi-faceted executive with an entrepreneurial mindset and extensive experience in developing and implementing transformational strategies that drive revenue, enable sustainable organizational growth, and optimize operations in hyper growth environments. Founding leadership member of many early-stage DTC + GTM programs & organizations across industry titans (Amazon, Samsung Electronics, Microsoft, and Apple) and privately held start-ups, each designed to increase brand awareness, market share, customer touchpoints, and physical footprints. Cultivates trusted business partnerships and stakeholder relationships at all levels. An influential servant leader building high-performing empowered teams focused on achieving the organization's goals and objectives. Creates organizational cultures of peak performance & continuous improvement by managing through vision & purpose, innovating, and delivering on immediate & long-range business objectives for expansion & scale. Defines company execution requirements, builds standards of work, and aligns entire organizations to credible financial performance, unified site operations & CX, and controlled quality across North America. Known as a change agent who leads teams successfully through ambiguity & transformation while maintaining exceptionally high morale, employee engagement, and employee retention.

"Lisa is a talented and engaging leader with a proven ability to energize teams to achieve challenging goals. She advanced quickly...to enable the business during a period of rapid scaling. Lisa played a key role building new capabilities during a period where the products and services we offered were evolving rapidly."

Tony Martinelli, Sr Leader (Amazon)

STRENGTHS

- Operations Leadership
- Strategic Planning
- Insights & Data Analysis
- Start-Up Operations
- Building Effective Teams

- Local & Global Practices
- Change Management
- Risk Management
- Resource Planning
- Market Expansion

- Cross-Functional Leadership
- Site & Marketplace Operations
- Project/Program Management
- P&L Ownership
- Organizational Transformation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SQUARERESULTS | CHICAGO, IL

Chief Operating Officer • 2023 to present

SquareResults is a specialized recruitment company with a vision to redefine the hiring process through cutting-edge technology and personalized service. It is a talent experience platform designed to provide a pipeline to make hiring easy. SquareResults's vision of becoming the leading recruitment agency in the industry, by providing high-quality services, innovative solutions, and personalized support to our clients and candidates. The organization develops and delivers cutting edge products for employers & candidates. As the COO, I'm responsible for driving operational excellence, strategic growth, and organizational success. Reporting directly to the CEO to achieve our business & product development objectives.

- Collaborate with the CEO to set the organizational vision, mission, and long-term strategy, creating growth & efficiency.
- Drive performance, operational planning, and execution while ensuring compliance.
- Lead IT, Marketing, Sales, Finance and Operations divisions to exceed expectations, build new products, and uphold our CSAT goals.
- Implement policies that promote our company culture, values, and vision.

METRO GROWTH INC | CHICAGO, IL

Founder • 2022 to 2024

Launched organization to enhance community and economic development by professionally upskilling citizens and extending operational and support services to small businesses and NFPs. Led public safety political campaigns and aligned with policing initiatives to reduce neighborhood crime in Chicago. Awarded Minority and Women's Business Enterprise (MBE/WBE) certifications by the City of Chicago.

- Ran full-cycle political campaign for my Police District Council candidacy in the 2023 Chicago Municipal Election, receiving endorsements from the Illinois Secretary of State, Chicago Aldermen, Cook County Assessor, and an IL State Representative.
- Participated in Candidate debates and developed grassroot marketing and canvassing strategies.
- Analyzed Chicago crime statistics, incident reports, and trends to develop local mitigation tactics.

LISA SEIGNEUR

UBER | CHICAGO, IL

Head of Operations - North America Driver Support • 2021 to 2022

Accountable for all aspects of physical Driver/Partner support sites in North America (Greenlights). Led a large organization of 400+ driver-facing employees to provide best-in-class service to empower drivers. Implemented standard operating procedures for onboarding and engagement of partners and led the team to innovate tomorrow's new best practices. Aligned local and global stakeholders around business objectives priorities, building competitive advantage by growing and strengthening the driver network.

- Provided leadership, management, and vision for the US&C Greenlight organization, consisting of >400 employees.
- Optimized the in person Greenlight operation's needs for growth and engagement of our driver-partners.
- Collected & reported on performance data, with a particular emphasis on trend identification and actionable insights.
- Developed, set, and obtained all operational aspects of the business, including core KPIs and an 8-figure budget.

AMAZON | CHICAGO, IL

Head of Operations - Smart Home Services • 2018 to 2021

Amazon Smart Home Services was a newly formed organization developed to increase Alexa (AI) devices' customer adoption, evangelize its hub integration with 3rd party smart products, and to build Alexa based Smart Home solutions. Initiating Amazon's first direct to consumer service, the program onboarded skilled Technicians and Licensed Tradesmen to perform in-home installations of Alexa and affiliate smart devices, educate consumers on product capabilities & possibilities, and grow AI product adoption. The organization grew a national field footprint and won many national homebuilder contracts to build & install Alexa based smart packages for its new construction homeowners (after homes' closing). During the Covid-19 pandemic, which halted field ops, the organization was acquired by Amazon's subsidiary and Smart Security product owner, RING, to also build & operate a virtual support, inside & direct sales division. The Smart Home Services org then operated both the Alexa and RING Smart Home & Smart Security business units concurrently.

As Head of Operations, solely led the Alexa Smart Home Services org's transition to RING, then was accountable for the operations & performance of both divisions. Complete oversight of the organization's P&L, strategic planning, growth, product development, account relations, negotiations, support operations, change management, virtual/field/HQ teams, vendor management, partner relations, and stakeholder enablement for the national footprint. Planned and managed cross-divisional programs. Led root cause analysis and implemented continuous improvement models, process automation, and workflow streamlining by swiftly identifying gaps, performance stallers, and waste across both org functions. Led division's culture & business transformation during business unit's migration and extreme ambiguity.

- Directed all national Field Ops functions including service delivery, customer enablement, in-home service fulfillment, CX, and ensured the safety of our 200+ field technicians and licensed tradesmen (4.95/5 Average Star Rating for program).
- Oversaw org's front and back end Amazon.com online marketplace (sku development/billing/service dispatching/fulfillment).
- Led the migration of the entire Amazon Smart Home Services' field operations & HQ support organization to the RING (smart home security) subsidiary. Upskilled the same teams to develop, launch, and enable new lines of business, products, and pre/post sale support functions that enabled new product developments & deployments across our Customers' portfolios (installed in 40,000 newly constructed homes annually).
- Hosted Townhall Meetings and created employee listening mechanisms to pulse, address, and resolve engagement/performance/CX blockers.
- Designed and implemented a revised org chart with new clearly defined role functions, leveling criteria, and career path
 progression which enhanced morale and team cultures and resulted in a 99% staff retention rate during the business unit's
 acquisition & beyond.
- Prepared and delivered Weekly/Monthly/Quarterly business reviews to Amazon's Device Org Executive Leadership & program sponsors.

SAMSUNG ELECTRONIC | CHICAGO, IL

District Sales Manager • 2014 to 2018

Samsung chartered its first physical DTC touchpoints by creating Samsung Experience Shops within National Retailers. These national brand footprints were launched and operated by Samsung direct & vendor staff to educate shoppers on its products' capabilities, offer Samsung device technical support, facilitate theater style educational product workshops, and increase direct sales of Samsung total solutions (entire ecosystem). Showcasing its cross-device/appliance integration resulted in improved U.S. brand market share. Due to the program's success, the organization grew to acquire all consumer field sales divisions across its U.S. partner/dealer sites and launched Samsung exclusive B&M stores.

As District Sales Manager, took ownership of field operations and brand presence across the largest territory in the US, a 1,500+ store region encompassing North Central, with responsibility for all National Retail locations plus all partner doors. Oversaw 10 direct reports,

LISA SEIGNEUR

120 indirects, 7 market managers, and staff from vendor labor providers (Mosaic, Premium Retail, 20/20). Expanded leadership to steer the totality of Samsung's presence & footprint within retail stores, growing regional revenue from \$183M to \$400M.

- Awarded "Top Sales District" for FY2015 and H12017 in sales achievement.
- Designed and owned a national ongoing Monthly Operations Execution Guide to streamline field communications and maintain brand consistency across the U.S. footprint (ultimately cascaded across other divisions within Samsung). This project centralized U.S. field operations workflows to uniform Samsung's brand consistency across all retail touchpoints.
- Launched, facilitated, and implemented 3 professional employee competency, career development, and succession planning systems to align U.S.' talent management & employee progression practices within the large field organization: (1) FYI: For Your Improvement by Lombardo & Eichinger, (2) Strengths Finder, (3) 9-Box Grid: Talent Calibration and Succession Planning.

MICROSOFT | SCHAUMBURG, IL General Manager • 2009 to 2014

Microsoft's then CEO (Steve Ballmer) and COO (Kevin Turner) sought to rival competitors by bringing the company's own exclusive Brick & Mortar stores to the U.S. Market ("Microsoft Store"). This launch and subsequent national market expansion resulted in building and operating 100+ global experiences stores (staffed with MS's direct employees) and a significant Omni-Channel online marketplace ("MicrosoftStore.com"). The program vastly improved Microsoft's brand recognition, ecosystem envisioning, market share, and presence. The B&M sites were directed to encompass Microsoft's overall internal culture, philanthropy, technology innovation, and commitment by being a place for customer platform conversion, a showroom for its Enterprise sales teams and partner network to conduct product & sales presentations, an educational center for non-profit orgs, local businesses and consumers, and be an overall public physical domain for all to experience the world of Microsoft & it's sizable product offerings.

Joined the corporation to guide the launch of the Microsoft Store program & centers across the US. Founding leadership member launching & operating Store #1 in Scottsdale, AZ, then replicated launch functions in many other early footprint locations across the U.S. Partnered with executive leadership and led stores' 50-mile radius omni-channel performance. Responsible for B2C, B2B, & Enterprise hardware Sales & Technical Support, market's Community & Business Development, and market's local Marketing teams. Defined scope requirements for new markets' outside sales operations, pipeline development, and local corporate citizenship initiatives while concurrently managing all newly launched store teams, internal functions, and site financial performance (owned P/L). Responsible for local media relations & PR.

- Executed multiple successful B&M launch operations and ongoing site business continuity across the U.S. (acquiring & onboarding local launch talent, engaging & integrating local MS Enterprise sales teams, creating and implementing market development plans, joining local community Commerce & Economic Development Chambers, and navigating & lobbying with local government).
- Grew post-launch local omni-channel revenue by 30% through ongoing community engagement, local marketing initiatives, and securing high impression title sponsorships, via self-developed strategies.
- Created & presented annual in-person business reviews to Microsoft's Executive Leadership Team (MS' CEO & COO). Fielded direct inquiries, collected corrective actions, and developed & executed urgent action & improvement plans.

INSTANT IMAGING PHOTOGRAPHY | CHICAGO, IL

Founder • 2003 to 2009

Created and operated this 15-person firm to photograph many of Chicago's ad-hoc and ongoing entertainment events. Built popular & profitable online subscription-based platform & marketplace for event attendees to view and purchase post-event images & portraits. Launched and operated new business lines (i.e. online platform affiliate marketing and client exclusive email marketing to our website's 30k+ subscriber base). Accountable for all ongoing company functions, grew the S-Corp to lead the industry's event photography & event digital marketing spaces, and serviced an average of 30 recurring weekly entertainment events.

APPLE | CHICAGO, IL

Senior Manager • 2001 to 2007

Founding leadership member of the Apple Retail Stores (recruited & onboarded prior to Store #1's opening). Launched, led, and operated Store #5 and multiple following B&M locations in Chicago. During the management of Chicago's flagship store (Michigan Avenue) I solely announced Apple's "Product (Red) iPod" on the Oprah Winfrey show, with Oprah herself & U2's lead singer, BONO.

CERTIFICATIONS

PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE | Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification, June 2024

EDUCATION

AUGUSTANA COLLEGE | Business Administration & Management